Finding Aid for American Association of Critical-Care Nurses. Washtenaw County Chapter records, 1982-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
American Association of Critical-Care Nurses. Washtenaw County Chapter records 1982-1992
American Association of Critical-Care Nurses. Washtenaw County Chapter.
3 linear ft. (4 boxes)
90148 Bf 2
Professional nursing association chapter established in 1982. Subject files relating to chapter activities; include chapter board and committee files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the organization (donor no. 7676 ) beginning in September 1989.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Washtenaw County Chapter of the American Association of Critical-Care Nurses was formed in 1982 and received its charter from the national organization in 1983. Part of the national group of more than 54,000 members, the Washtenaw County Chapter has as its goal the enhancement of critical care nurses' professional development. To this end, it sponsors annual symposia and other more frequent educational programs on topics which are integral to the work of critical care nurses, such as AIDS and heart transplantation.
The chapter is governed by an annually elected board, and its activities are managed through seven committees. The membership committee promotes recruitment and retention of members. The nominations committee recruits members to run for chapter office. The program committee coordinates monthly evening educational programs, including selection of topics and speakers. The publicity committee coordinates all aspects of the chapter newsletter and plans a September wine and cheese reception for prospective members. The strategic planning committee develops long-term chapter plans and goals. The symposium planning committee coordinates the annual spring symposium. There is also a committee that reviews and plans courses through which nurses can gain credit towards certification or recertification.
The records of the Washtenaw County Chapter of the American Association of Critical-Care Nurses consist of four series: History and Background, Administration, Committees, and Activities.
Subjects:
Intensive care nursing.; Nursing--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; American Association of Critical-Care Nurses. Washtenaw County Chapter.
- History and Background
  The History and Background series describes the formation and policies of the chapter.
  - Formation and Structure (Box 1)
  - History and Purpose (Box 1)
  - Policies and Procedures (Box 1)
- Administration
  The Administration series includes complete board minutes starting with the initial formation of the chapter and ending in April 1992.
  - Board minutes, 1982-1992, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Quarterly Financial reports, 1983-1991 (Box 1)
  - Unit Liaison purpose and function (Box 1)
- Committees
  The Committees series contains information relating to the various committees, the most complete of which are the Membership Committee records.
  - Marketing and Communication Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - Membership Committee information, 1981-1987, 1 expandable folder (Box 1)
  - Membership Drives, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Membership Committee minutes, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
  - Membership Promotion and Policy (Box 1)
  - Program Committee minutes, 1983-1989 (Box 1)
  - Publicity Committee, 1986-1989 (incomplete) (Box 1)
  - Spring Symposium Committee, 1982-1989, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Strategic Planning Committee, 1984-1985, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
- Activities
  The Activities series includes the Chapter of the Year Notebooks, which are helpful in gaining an overall view of the chapter goals and activities. The chapter submitted these notebooks for the yearly contest. The national office reviewed the chapters' activities, and acknowledged superlative achievements by awarding best chapter status.
  - Newsletter ("Monitor"), 1983-1988 (incomplete ), 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Programs, 1983-1992, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Spring Symposium, 1983-1988, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Legislative activities (Box 2)
  - Chapter of the Year Notebooks, 1986-1989, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Chapter of the Year Notebooks, 1987-1988, 2 notebooks (Box 3)
  - Chapter of the Year Notebook, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Chapter Operations Manual, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous later material (Box 4)